<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 14:41:58 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Linea Mini vs GS3</title>
      <link>/linea-mini-vs-gs3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 14:41:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linea-mini-vs-gs3/</guid>
      <description>La Marzocco is known for their handmade, quality home espresso machines and commercial espresso machines. They have been building coffee machines since 1927, and introduced us to the double-boiler machine, amongst other industry innovations that they have pioneered over their nearly a century in the coffee industry. If you&#39;ve been in the market for a home espresso machine, you have definitely come across these two popular machines, loved by home baristas everywhere!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Weigh Your Coffee</title>
      <link>/why-weigh-your-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 13:55:32 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/why-weigh-your-coffee/</guid>
      <description>From beans-to-brew your barista is weighing the entire process for the sake of your drink tasting the same every single time you walk through the door. Consistency in any industry is key and in coffee it couldn&#39;t be more important. Widely talked about in the barista world, and as many home baristas start to dial in their recipes, the question will often come up of weight versus volume.
Let&#39;s say they have used 17g of grinds and are pulling a 2oz shot, but something is off in the profile?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hibiscus Latte, The Perfect Spring Latte</title>
      <link>/hibiscus-latte-the-perfect-spring-latte/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 08:35:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/hibiscus-latte-the-perfect-spring-latte/</guid>
      <description>Spring is finally arrived in Upstate New York after frequent teasing by mother nature. As May rolls in with its wavering rainy days and sun flooded afternoons, this comforting sweet and floral recipe is the perfect last hot drink to curl up with as we wait for summer. The Hibiscus Latteis a great compliment to many coffees because, as you may have already noted, many varieties of beans naturally carry the subtle floral tea-like undertones in their flavor profile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How-To Make the Perfect Shot of Espresso</title>
      <link>/how-to-make-the-perfect-shot-of-espresso/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 11:06:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-to-make-the-perfect-shot-of-espresso/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&#39;re an experienced barista or a home espresso machine user you may struggle to pull the perfect espresso shot. There are many contributing factors and if you&#39;re new to the espresso world you&#39;ll definitely go through a bunch of coffee and bad shots. After decades in the business we have a couple of tips to improve your chances of making the perfect shot of espresso.
Firstly lets define what the World Barista Championship Rules and Regulations specify as espresso:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew Ratio</title>
      <link>/brew-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/brew-ratio/</guid>
      <description>You’ve got great beans, from a great roaster, who sourced the beans from an excellent farmer. That’s an ideal beginning for brewing a cup of coffee or espresso that will delight your palette, but a weak brew method can easily sour your hopes and dreams of brewing a great cup.
To perfect the process, it helps to understand all of the variables. We have the grind (solid particles) and hot water which extracts the essential solubles as the water flows over grind bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Boiler vs Dual Boiler</title>
      <link>/single-boiler-vs-dual-boiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 15:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/single-boiler-vs-dual-boiler/</guid>
      <description>When brewing espresso drinks there is a need for two different temperatures. Espresso is prepared best when the coffee is extracted at temperatures well below boiling point, around 198-204F. However, when it comes time to steam milk for lattes and other milk-based espresso drinks, this requires a large amount of steam at a temperature well above boiling.
There are varied methods that manufacturers use to tackle the issue of handling two temperature outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s the Difference Between Cold Brew and Iced Coffee?</title>
      <link>/whats-the-difference-between-cold-brew-and-iced-coffee/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Mar 2017 08:43:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/whats-the-difference-between-cold-brew-and-iced-coffee/</guid>
      <description>Since the recent popularity of cold brew coffee many consumers have wondered - what is the difference between cold brew and iced coffee? The main difference is the brewing method itself; cold brew is steeped with cold water for 12-48 hours, where iced coffee is brewed with hot water and then mixed with cold water and refrigerated. Both methods are relatively easy to execute, but the flavor profile achieved can be dramatically different.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Is Coffee Grown</title>
      <link>/how-is-coffee-grown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 09:23:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/how-is-coffee-grown/</guid>
      <description>Some of the best coffee beans in the world are grown between the Tropic of Cancer and the Tropic of Capricorn in and area known as the &#34;Coffee Belt&#34;. South America dominates coffee plantations with Brazil contributing more than 40% of all coffee production worldwide.
The coffee bean is actually a seed, and it is tucked inside the fruit of a coffee plant similar to a pit of a cherry. The two most common coffee beans are Arabica and Robusta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Filtration: What to Do When Your Water Isn&#39;t Up to Snuff</title>
      <link>/water-filtration-what-to-do-when-your-water-isnt-up-to-snuff/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2016 09:57:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/water-filtration-what-to-do-when-your-water-isnt-up-to-snuff/</guid>
      <description>So, you’ve done all of the research on which espresso machine is best for you and after what seems like forever, you make a decision and choose that a gorgeous direct plumbed espresso machine of your dreams. So why should I worry about the water?
Scale deposits - which are due to a high amount of carbonate hardness in your water. These deposits can cause several issues, the least of which is coffee, that does not taste as it should!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew With French Press</title>
      <link>/brew-with-french-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 10:21:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/brew-with-french-press/</guid>
      <description>As the saying goes, when in France do as the French do. Well, we’re not in France but you should definitely do as the French do when it comes to making coffee with a French Press. Some say that this classic coffee brewing method produces the best coffee with its rich and bold, yet clean taste. One of the reasons that the French Press brews such a great cup of coffee is because the concentrated, complex flavors of the beans are revealed when the water is in contact with the grounds for the entire brew process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/search/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>