<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reviews on </title>
    <link>/categories/reviews/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reviews on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 07:32:21 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/categories/reviews/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Doser or Doserless Coffee Grinder</title>
      <link>/doser-or-doserless-coffee-grinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 07:32:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/doser-or-doserless-coffee-grinder/</guid>
      <description>A debate of preference and application, not exactly over function, choosing between a doser or doserless coffee grinder there are a number of things to take into account. For everyone who takes coffee seriously – your beans are most important and logically your grinder next. That’s why the debate between a doser or doserless espresso grinder is a battle amongst coffee aficionados. There are five main factors in regard to your choice: price, consistency, volume, freshness, and cleanliness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linea Mini vs GS3</title>
      <link>/linea-mini-vs-gs3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 14:41:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/linea-mini-vs-gs3/</guid>
      <description>La Marzocco is known for their handmade, quality home espresso machines and commercial espresso machines. They have been building coffee machines since 1927, and introduced us to the double-boiler machine, amongst other industry innovations that they have pioneered over their nearly a century in the coffee industry. If you&#39;ve been in the market for a home espresso machine, you have definitely come across these two popular machines, loved by home baristas everywhere!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Single Boiler vs Dual Boiler</title>
      <link>/single-boiler-vs-dual-boiler/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2017 15:25:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/single-boiler-vs-dual-boiler/</guid>
      <description>When brewing espresso drinks there is a need for two different temperatures. Espresso is prepared best when the coffee is extracted at temperatures well below boiling point, around 198-204F. However, when it comes time to steam milk for lattes and other milk-based espresso drinks, this requires a large amount of steam at a temperature well above boiling.
There are varied methods that manufacturers use to tackle the issue of handling two temperature outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>