<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee Basics on </title>
    <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/categories/coffee-basics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coffee Basics on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.chriscoffee.com/categories/coffee-basics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew Ratio</title>
      <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/brew-ratio/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/brew-ratio/</guid>
      <description>You’ve got great beans, from a great roaster, who sourced the beans from an excellent farmer. That’s an ideal beginning for brewing a cup of coffee or espresso that will delight your palette, but a weak brew method can easily sour your hopes and dreams of brewing a great cup.
To perfect the process, it helps to understand all of the variables. We have the grind (solid particles) and hot water which extracts the essential solubles as the water flows over grind bed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Is Coffee Grown</title>
      <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/how-is-coffee-grown/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jan 2017 09:23:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/how-is-coffee-grown/</guid>
      <description>Some of the best coffee beans in the world are grown between the Tropic of Cancer and the Tropic of Capricorn in and area known as the &#34;Coffee Belt&#34;. South America dominates coffee plantations with Brazil contributing more than 40% of all coffee production worldwide.
The coffee bean is actually a seed, and it is tucked inside the fruit of a coffee plant similar to a pit of a cherry. The two most common coffee beans are Arabica and Robusta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brew With French Press</title>
      <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/brew-with-french-press/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2016 10:21:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/brew-with-french-press/</guid>
      <description>As the saying goes, when in France do as the French do. Well, we’re not in France but you should definitely do as the French do when it comes to making coffee with a French Press. Some say that this classic coffee brewing method produces the best coffee with its rich and bold, yet clean taste. One of the reasons that the French Press brews such a great cup of coffee is because the concentrated, complex flavors of the beans are revealed when the water is in contact with the grounds for the entire brew process.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>