<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coffee Grinder on </title>
    <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/tags/coffee-grinder/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coffee Grinder on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 10:04:17 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.chriscoffee.com/tags/coffee-grinder/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing the Right Baratza Coffee Grinder</title>
      <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/choosing-the-right-baratza-coffee-grinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 10:04:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/choosing-the-right-baratza-coffee-grinder/</guid>
      <description>As you start down your coffee journey it doesn&#39;t take long to realize the best coffee comes down to excellent equipment. Whether you&#39;re brewing at home, office, or commercial setting you want great flavor an consistency. Achieving optimal extraction of your coffee beans can&#39;t be done without a quality grinder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Doser or Doserless Espresso Grinder</title>
      <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/doser-or-doserless-espresso-grinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 May 2018 10:04:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/doser-or-doserless-espresso-grinder/</guid>
      <description>For everyone who considers coffee a religion – your beans are most important. Finding the best espresso grinder is an obvious second as your key to the best tasting coffee. The debate between the two types of espresso grinders seems to be a battle over preference. In our opinion though, choosing the best espresso grinder is about the application. In general, an on-demand, or doserless grinder, is best as a home espresso grinder.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Choosing an Espresso Grinder</title>
      <link>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/choosing-an-espresso-grinder/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2016 10:51:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.chriscoffee.com/choosing-an-espresso-grinder/</guid>
      <description>A consistent grind is hugely important in the process of making a high-quality cup of coffee, which is why the grinder is the most important piece of equipment when it comes to coffee preparation. Can it be more important than the actual machine itself? Yes, it can be. The grinder determines if the coffee you brew after you grind actually can be any good. Bad grind = bad coffee.
To prove the level of consistency of grind, we need a burr grinder and not a blade grinder.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>