<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>How To on </title>
    <link>https://chris-blog-86702.firebaseapp.com/tags/how-to/</link>
    <description>Recent content in How To on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 11:06:27 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://chris-blog-86702.firebaseapp.com/tags/how-to/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How-To Make the Perfect Shot of Espresso</title>
      <link>https://chris-blog-86702.firebaseapp.com/how-to-make-the-perfect-shot-of-espresso/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Apr 2018 11:06:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris-blog-86702.firebaseapp.com/how-to-make-the-perfect-shot-of-espresso/</guid>
      <description>Whether you&#39;re an experienced barista or a home espresso machine user you may struggle to pull the perfect espresso shot. There are many contributing factors and if you&#39;re new to the espresso world you&#39;ll definitely go through a bunch of coffee and bad shots. After decades in the business we have a couple of tips to improve your chances of making the perfect shot of espresso.
Firstly lets define what the World Barista Championship Rules and Regulations specify as espresso:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Tamp Espresso</title>
      <link>https://chris-blog-86702.firebaseapp.com/how-to-tamp-espresso/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 14:12:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chris-blog-86702.firebaseapp.com/how-to-tamp-espresso/</guid>
      <description>The importance of a good espresso tamp can easily be compared to the quality of grapes that go into making a fine wine. The tamping process involved in pulling a shot of espresso can be a make or break scenario. The reason why tamping is such a crucial part of this process is because it greatly affects the taste of the espresso. A ‘bad’ tamp will cause uneven extraction and channeling, where all the water goes through one part of the espresso rather than being evenly distributed throughout.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>